Guide to the William John Fielding Papers TAM.069
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II. Correspondence, 1912-1986; 465448
  - Correspondence: Hoffman, Robert, 1965-1968; 465490 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Hubbard, Elbert, 1912-1915; 465491 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Humanist Society of Greater New York, 1969-1973; 465492 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Hurd, Peter, July 1 ????; 465493 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: "I", 1938-1971; 465494 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Isenberg, Max, 1953-1966; 465495 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: "J", 1947-1972; 465496 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: "K", 1920-1973; 465497 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Karsner, David Fulton, 1917-1922; 465498 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Kelly, C.F. and Edith, 1917-1924; 465499 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Kemp, Robert, 1969-1971; 465500 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Kirkpatrick, George, 1916-1926; 465501 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Korzybski, Alfred, November 1922-September 1933; 465649 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: "L", 1915-1972; 465650 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Lamm, Lawrence, 1960-1972; 465651 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Leemans, Robert, 1965-1973; 465652 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Lewis, Joseph, 1923-1942; 465653 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Lewis, Joseph, 1943-1959; 465654 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Lewis, Joseph, 1961-1969; 465655 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Lindsey, Ben, 1939-1942; 465656 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: "M", 1933-1971; 465657 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Maddaloni, Arnold, 1959-1965; 465658 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Manhoff, Charles, 1963-1965; 465659 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Marquardt, John, 1960-1972; 465660 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: Martin, Martin J., 1964-1972; 465661 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: McKnight, George, editor "American Minds in Miniature." Includes: "Taking Sex Lore out of America's Back Alley" (3 pp.), 1931-1932; 465662 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Mead, Margaret, undated; 465663 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: Meagher, John, 1918-1919; 465664 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence: Meyer, Edward, 1955-1967; 465665 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence: Mitchell, Harold and Henry Winter, 1972-1973; 465666 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence: Monteith, William and Winnie, 1952-1973; 465667 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence: Morrell, Robert, 1970; 465668 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence: Moore, Louis de B., 1969-1972; 465669 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence: Morris, E. Denton, 1966-1971; 465670 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence: "N", 1919-1970; 465671 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence: New York Society for General Semantics (Allan Flass, President), 1961-1962; 465672 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence: New York Times, 1922-1973; 465673 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence: Nisbet, Mr. and Mrs. Alex, 1964-1969; 465674 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence: New Zealand Rationalist Association, 1963-1973; 465675 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence: "O", 1952; 465676 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence: O'Hair, Madalyn Murray, 1969-1972; 465677 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence: Olsen, Frieda, 1956-1972; 465678 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence: "P", 1918-1966; 465679 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Paine, Thomas Foundation, 1937-1971; 465680 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Paine, Thomas Society, 1971-1973; 465681 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Paiz, Joan, 1969-1972; 465682 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Paris, Dr. Sam; Mary and Delta Paris, 1961-1972; 465683 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Paul, Nishan and Lucy, 1964-1972; 465684 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Pi Gamma Mu, 1928-1936; 465685 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Publisher Rejection Letters, 1935-1973; 465686 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Progressive World, 1961-1973; 465687 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: "Q", 1952; 465688 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: "R", 1918-1973; 465689 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Reiss, Louis and Mona, 1949-1972; 465690 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Reitmeister, Dr. Louis, 1970-1971; 465691 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Reuben, Jack, 1956-1971; 465692 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Robinson, Dr. Victor, 1920-1921; 465693 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Robinson, Dr. William, 1917-1932; 465694 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Russell, Bertrand, 1958; 465695 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Ryan, William, 1969-1973; 465696 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: "S", 1921-1972; 465697 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Sanford, Natalie and Sandy, 1952-1973; 465698 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Sanger, Margaret, 1917-1929, 1963-1966; 465699 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Sauer, Emile, 1963; 465700 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Schiltz, Joseph, 1963; 465701 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Schmalhausen, Samuel, 1923-1928; 465702 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Sessions, Alanson, 1918; 465703 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Seto, Yoshinao, 1920-1922; 465704 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Shatter, Fritzie and Saul, 1958-1978; 465705 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Shapiro, Irma, 1972-1973; 465706 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Shulmin, Herman, 1931-1970; 465707 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Shur, Cantor and Ira, 1960-1967; 465708 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Sinclair, Upton, 1918-1928; 465709 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Smith, Harold and Belle, 1957-1972; 465710 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Smith, Ramsey, 1921-1925; 465711 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Smith, William Hawley, 1920-1922; 465712 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Society for Ethical Culture (N.Y.), 1948-1972; 465713 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: South Australia (the McCalls, the Camerons, etc.), 1968-1973; 465714 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Spock, Dr. Benjamin, 1966-1977; 465715 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Sprott, Florilda, 1970; 465716 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Stein, Gordon, 1968-1970; 465717 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Stein, Otto, March 1971-August 1972; 465718 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Stix, Dr. Louis, 1952-1968; 465719 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Stopes, Dr. Marie, 1920-1927; 465720 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Surkenik, Julia, 1971-1973; 465721 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: Swanson, Joanne, 1972; 465722 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: Swasey, Robert, 1924-1926; 465723 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Sylvester, Belle and Arnold, 1961-1971; 465724 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: "T", 1919-1972; 465725 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence: Thompson, Muriel and Tom, 1968-1973; 465726 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence: Thor, Milton, 1961-1969; 465727 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence: Tiffany Enterprises (Alphabetical by Correspondent), 1916-1973; 465728 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence: Tiffany Family and Foundation, 1918-1971; 465729 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence: Tolstoy, Count Leo Jr., Letter to Louis TIffany, October 1926; 465730 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence: "U", 1963-1969; 465731 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence: "V", 1920-1971; 465732 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence: Vining, Kay, 1965-1972; 465733 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence: "W", 1917-1972; 465734 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence: Wakefield, Sherman, 1938-1971; 465735 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence: Weber, Mary Louise, 1961-1972; 465736 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence: Weston, Ross Allen, 1965-1968; 465737 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence: Whitten, K.M., 1965-1967; 465738 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence: Wood, Charles, 1915-1923; 465739 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence: Wortman, Fred, 1952; 465740 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence: "Y", 1970-1972; 465741 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Personal Photographs, circa late 1950s-1970s; 465785 (Box A001)
- Series III. Writings, 1911-1973; 465742
  Series III: Writings contains two typescripts of Fielding's autobiography, All the Lives I Have Lived (Dorrance and Co., 1972), and other published and unpublished works, including poems, essays, and reviews written by Fielding over the years, several on free thought and freethinkers. Fielding's writings also include the unpublished typescripts "The Plight of the Aged Middle-Class Sick," the personal history of an aging, middle-class individual in America between 1960 and 1973, "Thomas Paine Returns to Thetford," and "Reminiscences About Alfred Korzybski."
  - Writings: "Abortion, Murder and the Godly" (W.J.F), Progressive World, 1969; 465743 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Writings: "All the Lives I Have Lived" (Manuscript, W.J.F.), 1972; 465746 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Writings: "All the Lives I Have Lived" (Duplicate Manuscript, W.J.F.), 1972; 465747 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Writings: "All the Lives I Have Lived" Correspondence and Reviews, 1968-1973; 465748 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Writings: "Arrested, I Waived Extradition" (W.J.F.), undated; 465744 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Writings: "Atheism is a Positive Philosophy" (W.J.F.), Progressive World, 1972; 465745 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Writings: Autobiographical Material (letters, etc) Used in Connection with the Publication of "All the Lives I Have Lived", 1920-1972; 465750 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Writings: "Birth Control in America" by David M. Kennedy (Review, W.J.F.), undated; 465751 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Writings: "Burns the Rebel..." (W.J.F.), undated; 465752 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Writings: "A Century of Turbulent Activities" (Review, W.J.F.), undated; 465753 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Writings: by Correspondents, 1952-1970; 465754 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Writings: "The Corruptiveness of Power" (W.J.F.), Progressive World, 1968; 465755 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Writings: "The Decline and Fall of Romerica" (W.J.F.), undated; 465756 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Writings: "Flight from Reality" (W.J.F.), Ethical Outlook, May 1956; 465757 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Writings: "Government by Gimmick" (W.J.F.), The Churchman, undated; 465758 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Writings: "I Returned from the Dead: Some Personal and Philosophical Reflections There On" (W.J.F.), The Age of Reason Magazine, September 1965; 465760 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Writings: "I Would Not Care to Be That Man" (W.J.F.), undated; 465761 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Writings: "Joseph Lewis: A Reminiscence" (W.J.F.), American Rationalist, January 1969; 465762 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Writings: "Joseph McCabe: A Career Extraordinary" (W.J.F.), The American Rationalist, undated; 465763 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Writings: "A Long Neglected American Patriot Emerges from Obscurity: Button Gwinnett Reveled as an Amazing, Enigmatic Personality" (Typescript, W.J.F), undated; 465764 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Writings: "Margaret Sanger: Pioneer of the Future" by Emily Taft Douglas (Review, W.J.F.), Progressive World, September 1970; 465765 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Writings: "The New 'God is Dead' Theologians" (W.J.F.), The American Rationalist, undated; 465766 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Writings: "A Night Without Dick" (W.J.F.), undated; 465767 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Writings: "The Paradox of the Roman Catholic Hierarchy" (W.J.F.), The American Rationalist, 1966; 465768 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Writings: "Periodic Cataclysms of the Earth" (W.J.F.), The Age of Reason Magazine, November 1967; 465769 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Writings: "The Plight of the Aged Middle-Class Sick" (W.J.F.), undated; 465770 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Writings: Poetry by W.J.F., 1913-1967; 465771 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Writings: Printed Ephemera Relating to Psychology, Sexology, and Other Matters (early 1920s), 1918-1934; 465772 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Writings: "Reminiscences About Alfred Korzybski", 1962; 465773 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Writings: Richards, Kenneth, "The Rotating Earth to be Belted to the Wheels of a Super Industrialism: Prediction of Primal Power Sources in Another Century" (Manuscript), 1911; 465774 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Writings: "Satisfactions of an Ethical Society" (W.J.F.), The Age of Reason Magazine, September 1968; 465775 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Writings: "The Scotch Under a Microscope" (W.J.F.), The Modern Thinker 7:4 (1935): 30-34, December 1935; 465776 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Writings: Sketch Book Magazine (W.J.F, Dramatic Editor; also includes articles by W.J.F), 1927-1932; 465777 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Writings: "The Sordid Picture of a Corrupted Land" (W.J.F.), Progressive World, September 1966; 465778 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Writings: "The Tarnished Presidency" (W.J.F.), undated; 465779 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Writings: "Thomas Pain Returns to Thetford" (W.J.F., typescript), undated; 465780 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Writings: "To Be Fully Alive" by Arnold Maddaloni (Review, W.J.F.), undated; 465781 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Writings: "What Are Your Dreams Trying to Tell You" (W.J.F.) Journal of Living 17:12, pp 79-98, January 1952; 465782 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Writings: "What if Christ Had Never Lived? Assuming, Of Course, That He Had" (W.J.F.), The American Rationalist, 1970; 465783 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Series IV. Addendum, 565709
  - Poster, undated; 565710 (Flat-file 6, Drawer 8)
    The front of the poster is titled "Know Thyself" with text by William John Fielding and E. Haldeman-Julius. The backs of the poster is titled "Life and Letters" with text by E. Haldeman-Julius. The poster is an advertisement for subscription to these publications.